Khoa Pham

Senior Front-end Developer

Profile

With background of computer science and over 7+ years of experience with web application development. My passion is to write clean code and develop good UX. I like working on the front-end because it helps delivering direct experience to users.

Experience

Senior Application Engineer - Nike Valiant Labs

01/2018 - Present

Work with many teams at Nike Valiant Labs to help bringing their new ideas to life. Architect and implement prototype for product quickly. Collaborate and mentor other junior developers.

UI Developer II, Healthsparq - Cambia Health Solutions 12/2016 - 01/2018

Work with talented Healsparq team to build products that reinvent healthcare industries for a better and transparent healthcare.

Senior Front-end Developer, Seastar.io

03/2015 - 12/2016

Lead of front-end development to design and create intuitive web application for Seastar dashboard using EmberJS, D3.js, Go, Cassandra.

Web Application Engineer, The Program PDX

10/2014 - 03/2015

Take technical ownership of projects and be responsible for architecting and developing complex digital solutions using full-stack development.

Web Developer, Sincerely Truman (Epipheo)

08/2011 - 10/2014

Lead of front-end to develop complex websites and applications. Build highly customized Wordpress themes and Wordpress plugins.

Labs Technician and Server Operations, Portland State University 06/2010 - 08/2012

Work with server operations team to mange Portland State datacenter. Support staffs and students at PSU for computer software and hardware.

Education

BS. Computer Science, Portland State University

2009 - 2012

Advanced Computer Science Program, Vietnam National University 2007 - 2009

Contact

⊠ khoa.pham@me.com

www.khoapham.me

@pmkhoa

github.com/pmkhoa

Tech Skills

Front-end

React, Redux, NextJS, EmberJS, GraphQL, Apollo, D3, ThreeJS, TweenMax.

Programming Languages

Javascript, Go, PHP, Ruby, Java, HTML.

Database

Postgres, Graphql, MySQL.

Frameworks

Ember, Rails, ExpressJS, Wordpress, Go Web API.

DevOps

AWS, Lamda, Linux Server, Docker, Serverless.

Work Tools

Vim, Tmux, Git, Sketch, Slack.

UX

Photoshop, Sketch, sharp eyes for UI and UX design.

Hobbies

Practice meditation

Learn latest technology

Cooking

Play with my kids